hi folks its Matt Jackson again so we're
大家好，再次是Matt Matt Jackson，所以我们
here and now we're talking about an
在这里，现在我们正在谈论
application of sub-game perfect
子游戏完美的应用
reasoning and we're looking at what's
推理，我们正在研究什么
known as ultimatum bargaining so let's
被称为最后通bar的讨价还价，所以让我们
have a peek so ultimatum bargaining is
偷看，所以最后通bar的议价是
probably one of the simplest bargaining
可能是最简单的讨价还价之一
games you could imagine it's sort of a
您可以想象的游戏有点像
take-it-or-leave-it offer kind of
接受或离开提供某种
bargaining that you might have heard of
您可能听说过的讨价还价
about in popular folklore so the idea
关于民间传说
here is is let's say that there's 10
这是说有十个
units to be split between two players
由两个玩家分配的单位
and in particular we'll take these two
特别是我们将把这两个
be say integer units so we have say ten
可以说是整数单位，所以我们可以说十
dollars ten euros ten whatever's to
美元十欧元十美元
split between two players and they have
在两个玩家之间分配，他们有
to agree in order to get anything so
同意以便得到任何东西
player one makes an offer says okay look
玩家提出要约说好
here you can have six I'll keep the rest
在这里你可以有六个，我会剩下的
and then player two can accept or reject
然后第二个玩家可以接受或拒绝
and based on what happens then if player
然后根据发生的情况，如果玩家
two accepts the offer so if X is the
两个人接受了要约，所以如果X是
offer that's made and player two accepts
提供的报价，第二个玩家接受
then player two gets whatever was
然后玩家二得到什么
offered and player one gets the
提供，玩家一获得
remainder if it's rejected then
其余的如果被拒绝的话
everybody gets zero so in this case you
每个人都为零，所以在这种情况下，您
only reach something if it's an
只有达到目标
agreement and this is one-shot
同意，这是一枪
bargaining in the sense that the there's
在某种意义上讲讨价还价
just one offer made and an accept or
只是一个要约和一个接受或
reject they can't go back and forth so
拒绝他们不能来回走
it doesn't alternate they don't get the
这不会交替，他们不会得到
chance to come back to the table and so
有机会回到桌子上，所以
forth it's just here take it or leave it
出来就在这里，拿走或离开它
if you don't want it forget it so that's
如果您不想让它忘记它，那就是
the idea okay
好主意
so let's analyze this game using stuff
所以让我们用东西来分析这个游戏
game perfection you can actually write
您可以实际编写的游戏完美
it out the tree for this you know still
为此，你仍然知道
manageable so player 1 moves first they
易于管理，因此玩家1首先移动
could offer x equals 0 1 2 etc all the
可以提供x等于0 1 2等等
way up to 10 then player 2 move second
上升到10，然后玩家2移至第二
they can accept or reject the offer so
他们可以接受或拒绝要约，因此
they can reject they can accept and
他们可以拒绝，他们可以接受，
based on what the the offers are they're
根据要约是什么
going to get different payoffs right so
将会获得不同的回报，所以
the payoffs here if they reject
如果他们拒绝，这里的收益
everybody gets 0 in each case if an
如果一个
offer is
报价是
made of ten and it's accepted player two
由十个组成，并且被接受为第二个玩家
gets ten player one gets zero for an
赢得十个玩家，一个获得零
offer of six is made and it's accepted
提出了六个报价并被接受
player two gets six player one gets for
玩家二拿六玩家一拿
an offer of one is made and it's
要约一个被提出
accepted player two gets one player one
被接受的玩家二获得一名玩家一
gets nine and so forth right so that's
得到九等等，所以
the structure of the game very simple
游戏的结构非常简单
and you can solve this directly by
您可以通过直接解决
backward induction or sub game
向后归纳或子博弈
perfection what's true well when we
完美，当我们
think about the player two they should
想想他们应该选的两个球员
accept any offer which is positive right
接受任何积极的权利
so any offer which is positive you get a
因此，任何积极的报价都会得到
positive payoff who you accept it zero
正收益，您接受谁为零
if you don't they should go ahead and
如果你不这样做，他们应该继续前进，
accept any one of those authors at at
在接受其中任何一位作者
zero in that case it looks like one
在那种情况下为零
where the second player is actually
第二个玩家实际上在哪里
indifferent so what they do is up to
漠不关心，所以他们的工作取决于
them at that point so if they're offered
他们在那个时候，所以如果他们被提供
0 they might say yes they might say no
0他们可能会说是，他们可能会说不
they could mix they could randomize so
他们可以混合他们可以随机
we're not sure exactly what's going to
我们不确定到底会发生什么
happen in that part of the tree but what
发生在树的那部分，但是
is true is that since they should be
的确是因为他们应该
accepting all of these things we do know
接受我们知道的所有这些事情
that a best best reply for player one
给玩家一个最好的答复
given what they anticipate happening in
鉴于他们预期发生的事情
the second thing should never be to make
第二件事永远不要做
an offer which involves more than one
一项涉及多个
two player to write so they can get nine
两个球员写，所以他们可以得到九
by offering this which they know will be
通过提供他们知道的
accepted whether they want to go down
接受他们是否想下去
here depends on what their beliefs are
这取决于他们的信仰
about what player 2 is going to do here
关于玩家2将要在这里做什么
but basically once we've assumed that
但是基本上，一旦我们假设
once we've deduced that player 2 is
一旦我们推断出玩家2是
going to accept any positive offer then
然后接受任何积极的报价
given that the player 1 gets a higher
给定玩家1更高
payoff from the lowest possible amount
从最低的可能的收益
they're going to offer player 2 at most
他们最多会提供玩家2
1 right so we get a pretty direct
1对，这样我们就可以直接获得
prediction player 2 accepts any positive
预测玩家2接受任何肯定
thing player 1 is going to offer either
玩家1将要提供的东西
0 or 1 depending on two's decision at 0
0或1，取决于两个人在0时的决定
but in a sub game perfect equilibrium
但在子游戏中达到完美平衡
we have a prediction that two or more
我们预测两个或更多
would never be offered okay so let's
永远不会被提供，所以让我们
have a look these are some data from
看看这些是一些数据
online games played last year and in the
去年和
game theory course and let's have a look
博弈论课程，让我们来看看
at what actually were played so here are
实际演奏的是这里
the offers how much was offered to the
报价给了多少
second player and in fact you can see
第二个玩家，实际上你可以看到
that five was the modal offer offered
那五个是模态报价
more than 2000 times the next highest
超过第二高的2000倍
offer of one which is the prediction or
提供一个预测或
one of the predictions of the sub game
子游戏的预测之一
perfect equilibrium was slightly less
完美平衡稍差
than a thousand and we can also look at
超过一千，我们也可以看看
the acceptance so here the way this
这样的接受方式
worked is players were asked what's the
工作是玩家被问到是什么
minimal amount that you would be willing
您愿意的最低金额
to accept and the theory predicts that
接受，理论预测
everybody should should be saying either
每个人都应该说
0 or 1
0或1
they should never be rejecting offers
他们不应该拒绝报价
the of at least one so the minimal
至少一个的最小
amount they should be accepted to be at
他们应该被接受的数量
least sorry at most 1 and here we see
至少对不起1，在这里我们看到
that actually a majority of the players
实际上大多数玩家
are in fact put setting their minimal
实际上将其设置为最小
acceptance at higher and a lot of them
更高的接受度
hold out for point 4 5 50% so in fact
支持点4 5 50％，所以实际上
when we look at the data here the data
当我们在这里查看数据时
are not congruent with what sub game
与什么子游戏不一致
perfection is predicting and you know
完美在预言，你知道
when you when you think about what the
当你想到什么
best offer is for a given player given
最佳报价是给定的给定玩家
the strategies that are being played
正在采取的策略
here so when we look at the acceptance
在这里，所以当我们看验收
rate so if I knew that this is what the
率，所以如果我知道这就是
population is doing suppose I know that
人口正在做，假设我知道
this is the way people are acting in
这就是人们的行为方式
terms of what they're going to accept
他们将接受的条款
what should I offer well there's some
我应该提供些什么？
chance I'm going to meet somebody who's
机会我会遇到一个
only going to accept 5 at least 5 I had
我只会接受5个，至少5个
a pretty fair chance that if I offered
一个相当公平的机会，如果我愿意
something above 5 it would almost
高于5的东西几乎
certainly be accepted
当然会被接受
but whether it has to be five or whether
但是否必须是五个
I drop all the way down to one that's
我一路下降到那个
going to depend on who I happen to meet
取决于我碰巧遇到谁
and if you look at my expected payoff my
如果你看看我的预期收益
expected payoff my best payoff is
预期收益我最好的收益是
actually to offer to offer five given
实际上提供要约
what the players are doing in terms of
玩家在做什么方面
their acceptance and so when we go back
他们的接受，所以当我们回去
to the play here the fact that that
在这里玩的事实是
these players are playing five is
这些球员打五是
consistent with what the players are
与玩家是一致的
doing in the second stage so where sub
在第二阶段做，所以子
game perfection is missing things in
游戏完美性缺失
here so players here are a lot of them
这里的球员很多
are best replying to the actual
最好回复实际
distribution that they're facing it's
他们面对的分布是
really the acceptance rejection part
真的是验收拒绝部分
which is which is contradicting what the
这是矛盾的
sub game perfect play would have and you
子游戏完美玩法会和你
know there's different explanations for
知道有不同的解释
this we could think you know in terms of
我们可以认为您知道
why we're seeing this particular play it
为什么我们看到这个特别的游戏
could be that players for instance are
举例来说，可能是
you know have strong aversion to
你知道对
anything that's unequal and what that
任何不平等的东西
means then is that the payoff that we've
那就意味着我们已经获得了回报
written into this matrix of 1 2 3 4 5
写入1 2 3 4 5的矩阵
and so forth is not the actual payoff
等等不是实际的收益
that people have maybe they have
人们有也许他们有
disutility of getting less than another
徒劳无益
person and that makes them feel really
人，这让他们感到非常
badly and and they want to avoid that
非常糟糕，他们想避免这种情况
bad feeling and so their utility might
不好的感觉，所以他们的效用可能
actually represent something which
实际代表的东西
includes equity concerns for instance
包括股权问题
that's one possibility you know there's
你知道那是一种可能性
a lot of alternative explanations it
很多其他的解释
could be that they they always want to
可能是他们一直想要的
have more than the other player or you
比其他玩家或您拥有更多
know you could think of different kinds
知道你会想到不同的种类
of things which would govern different
决定不同的事物
kinds of play so there's some players
各种各样的比赛，所以有一些球员
who just seem to be taking whatever they
他们似乎正在采取任何他们
can other players who seem to be pushing
其他看似在推动的玩家可以
for an equal split and somehow feeling
对于平等的分裂和某种感觉
it that's what the the minimal amount
这就是最小的数量
that they would be willing to accept one
他们愿意接受一个
other possible conjecture that people
人们可能的其他猜想
have brought up a number of times is
提出了很多次是
that maybe the stakes aren't large
可能赌注不大
enough so you know for instance when we
足够，所以你知道例如当我们
played this online the the players were
在网上玩过，玩家们
playing this
玩这个
in terms of a question they weren't
在一个问题上，他们不是
actually paid for it maybe if we paid
实际付款了，如果我们付款了
them you know suppose you're now
他们他们知道你现在就知道了
splitting instead of 10 fictional units
拆分而不是10个虚构单元
you're splitting ten million dollars or
您要拆分一千万美元，或者
ten million euros are you going to
你要一千万欧元
reject an offer of four million of that
拒绝其中四百万的报价
if somebody says okay you can have four
如果有人说可以的话，你可以有四个
million I'll take I'll keep six million
我要拿六百万
are you gonna say no probably not so one
你会说不，也许不是吗
possibility is you know to see whether
可能是你知道看是否
the size of the pie matters and so here
馅饼的大小很重要，所以在这里
are some interesting experiments to try
有一些有趣的实验可以尝试
and test that hypothesis maybe it's just
并检验假设，也许只是
that you know we're not paying people
你知道我们不付钱给人
enough to to see that they're the real
足以看到他们是真实的
rational behavior so there's a nice
理性的行为，所以有一个很好的
paper by Robert Slonim and Al Roth and
Robert Slonim和Al Roth的论文，以及
Al Roth one just won a Nobel Prize this
罗斯（Al Roth）刚刚获得诺贝尔奖
year and and what they're looking at
年以及他们在看什么
here is is learning in high stakes
这是学习高额赌注
ultimatum games and to make things high
最后通games游戏和使事情高涨
stakes what they did is they went to
赌注他们所做的是他们去了
Slovakia the Slovak Republic and they
斯洛伐克斯洛伐克共和国和他们
they did three different versions of
他们做了三种不同的版本
this
这个
so one where people could split 60
所以人们可以分开60
Slovak crowns one where they could split
斯洛伐克加冕他们可以分开的地方
300 Slovak crowns and another word they
300斯洛伐克克朗和另一个词
could split 1500 and the average monthly
可以拆分1500，平均每月
wage right so per month you're getting
正确的工资，所以每月
5500 so when you're getting up to 1500
5500，所以当您起床到1500
you're talking about more than a week's
你在谈论一个多星期的时间
wage right so you're looking at offering
工资合适，所以您正在考虑提供
somebody a week salary to be split
某人一个星期的工资要分摊
so now arguably the money at stake is
所以现在可以说这笔钱危在旦夕了
reasonably large right so the high
相当大的权利，所以高
stakes version is is on the order of a
赌注的版本大约是
week's wage okay
一周的工资还可以
so what happened so what they did here
所以发生了什么，他们在这里做了什么
is they had a thousand units so instead
他们有一千个单位，所以
of just splitting things one two three
一二三的分裂
four five to ten you could split it in
四五到十，你可以分成
units of a thousand where the you know
你知道的千单位
the full thousand correspondent in the
的一千名通讯员
first game to the 60 crowns in the
第一场比赛达到60冠
second game to three hundred and so
第二局到三百左右
forth right so one unit and this would
正确，所以一个单位，这将
be 1.5 Slovak crowns and the 1500
1.5斯洛伐克克朗和1500
treatment and so the question is then
治疗，所以问题是
how much was offered to the other player
向其他玩家提供了多少
on average well 451 in the first game
在第一场比赛中平均451
the low stakes game 460 in the middle
中低筹码游戏460
423 in the higher stakes game so it did
在高赌注游戏中为423，所以
go down a little
下去一点
but certainly not down to one which
但当然不能归结为哪一个
would be the prediction of sub-game
将是子游戏的预测
perfect at the medians they're very
在中位数很完美，他们非常
similar 465 480 450 so a little bit
类似465 480 450，所以有点
people are shading a little bit below
人们在下面加阴影
50% but they're not pushing too much
50％但他们并没有努力
further than 50% and when we look at the
超过50％，当我们观察
rejection offer so let's look just for
拒绝报价，让我们看看
instance at when people offered less
当人们提供较少的实例
than 250 out of the 1000 to the second
千分之二至千分之二
mover how often was that rejected well
搬家工人被拒绝的频率有多高
it was it wasn't offered that frequently
那不是经常提供
in the low stakes game it was only
在低赌注游戏中，这只是
offered once and it was rejected but in
提供一次，但被拒绝，但在
the middle stakes game it was rejected
中间赌注游戏被拒绝了
about half the time 10 out of 20 and in
大约一半的时间是20分之10
the higher stakes game it was on the
赌注较高的游戏
order of a third 12 out of 32 so a
在32的三分之一中排序为12
little more than a third but what we do
三分之一多一点，但我们做什么
see is is you know subject to
看是你知道服从
statistical significance here basically
基本上在这里具有统计意义
we get a comparison between these two we
我们将两者进行比较
are seeing as we up the stakes people
在看到我们举足轻重的人
are pushing down and rejecting really
在推倒并拒绝
lower offers less frequently but it's
较低的报价频率较低，但这是
not going all the way down and still the
不会一直走下去，仍然
the offers that are being made on
正在进行的报价
average are fairly high okay so what do
一般都很高，那该怎么办
we learn from this
我们从中学习
well sub-game perfection does not always
子游戏的完美并不总是
match the data and if you go back to
匹配数据，如果您返回
this game and you think about the Nash
这个游戏，你会想到纳什
equilibria any one of the offers can be
平衡任何一项报价都可以
supported as part of a Nash equilibrium
作为纳什均衡的一部分得到支持
right so it could be that I make that
对，所以可能我做了
offer because I think it's the only one
提供，因为我认为这是唯一的
that the other person's going to be
另一个人将会是
willing to accept and indeed they accept
愿意接受，实际上他们接受
it and I never know whether they would
它，我永远不知道他们是否会
have rejected the other one so there's
已经拒绝了另一个，所以有
lots of Nash equilibria to this game and
这个游戏有很多纳什均衡
sub game perfection is picking a few of
子游戏的完美选择
them out and in some cases you know
他们出来，在某些情况下，你知道
these violate rationality but
这些违反了理性，但
rationality where we believe that the
我们认为
payoffs are just exactly the monetary
收益恰好是金钱
amounts and not something else right so
数量而不是其他的东西，所以
it could be that we have the payoffs
可能是我们有回报
incorrect it written down incorrectly
不正确的写下来不正确
people could value equity they could be
人们可以珍惜他们可能成为的平等
feeling emotions
感受情绪
so there's a whole area of game theory
所以整个博弈论领域
which is basically expanded and more or
基本上是扩展的，或者更多
less exploded in the last couple of
在最近的几个爆炸较少
decades where people begin to analyze
人们开始分析的几十年
motivations of players other kinds of
玩家的其他动机
concerns that they might have called
他们可能已经打电话给他们的担忧
behavioral game theory and it it moves
行为博弈论及其动因
away from the very narrow definitions of
远离狭义的定义
rationality which are that we just look
我们只是看的合理性
directly at some very specific monetary
直接以一些非常具体的货币
or simple payoff and are looking at
或简单的回报，正在寻找
either expanding the way in which
要么扩大
payoffs are there or bringing in other
收益存在或带来其他
kinds of biases or tendencies that
各种偏见或倾向
people might have to understand things
人们可能必须了解事物
and that can expand and help games so
这样可以扩展和帮助游戏，
over all of them you know when we look
对他们所有人，当我们看着
at sub game perfect and what we've
在完美的子游戏中，我们所拥有的
learned from it the the basic premise
从中学到的基本前提
and I think the one of the important
而且我认为重要的之一
things to take away from studying sub
学习潜艇带走的东西
game perfection is that it imposes
游戏的完美之处在于
sequential rationality so it's a certain
顺序合理性
kind of logic and whether or not people
逻辑以及人们是否
play that way understanding the logic
以这种方式理解逻辑
helps us understand the the incentives
帮助我们了解激励措施
in the game better and at least gives us
在游戏中更好，至少给了我们
some feeling for the game so they result
对游戏有一些感觉，所以他们结果
some game perfection and backward
一些游戏的完善和落后
induction we generally will pick out a
归纳，我们通常会挑选一个
subset of the Nash equilibria and
纳什均衡的子集和
they're doing that by sort of imposing a
他们通过强加一个
credibility in circumstances that are
在以下情况下的信誉
never reached right so there's this idea
从来没有达到正确的，所以有这个想法
of what's happening off the equilibrium
平衡发生了什么
path can actually be important in
路径实际上在以下方面很重要
determining what people are doing and
确定人们在做什么，
you want to make sure that that the
您要确保
prescription of what players are going
球员要做什么的处方
to do in all these circumstances is
在所有这些情况下要做的是
credible one thing that it's very
可信的一件事，这是非常
interesting to start thinking about when
开始思考何时有趣
you think about sub game perfection what
您认为完美的子游戏是什么
about the game of chess chess is
关于国际象棋的游戏
actually a game of complete information
实际上是一个完整的信息游戏
right so you could write down a tree for
对，所以你可以写下一棵树
chess if you had a lot of time on your
国际象棋，如果你有很多时间
hands the first player can make a bunch
第一手牌手可以制造一堆
of moves the second player can then make
第二个玩家可以做出的动作
a bunch of moves the third player I'm
一堆动作，我是第三位玩家
sorry the first player then again gets
对不起，第一个玩家然后再次获得
to make a move and and so you've got a
采取行动，所以你有一个
tree which can be written out and it's
可以写出来的树
actually a finite game a very big but a
实际上是一个有限的游戏，很大，但是
finite game in the sense that if the
在某种意义上说，如果
same board has ever reached three times
同一块板曾达到三遍
the game end so so there are ending
游戏结束，所以结束了
which make sure that the game doesn't go
确保游戏不会进行
on infinitely so it's actually a finite
在无限上，所以实际上是有限的
extensive form game of complete
完整的广泛形式游戏
information so at least theoretically
信息，至少理论上如此
you could solve chess but obviously we
你可以解决国际象棋，但显然我们
haven't managed to do that and and it's
尚未做到这一点，这是
just such a large game that solving the
这么大的游戏，解决了
sub game perfect equilibria that seem to
子游戏的完美平衡似乎
be impossible maybe on another planet
不可能在另一个星球上
they've solved a chess and they could be
他们解决了国际象棋，他们可能会
that they think of it as like our
他们认为它就像我们的
tic-tac-toe which is a much simpler game
井字游戏，这是一个简单得多的游戏
to solve and after you've played it a
解决，在您玩过之后
few times you get pretty bored by it one
几次，你对此感到无聊
other thing that's important is is you
另一个重要的是你
know even with a game where it's
即使在游戏中也知道
dominant solvable and so forth sorry not
占主导地位的可解决的等等，对不起
a dominant solvable but solvable by a
占主导地位的可解决但被一个人解决
backward induction or sub game
向后归纳或子博弈
perfection it's it's not completely
完美不是完全
clear that everybody abides by the logic
清楚每个人都遵守逻辑
and in particular you need to believe in
特别是你需要相信
the rationality of others right so you
别人的合理性对吧
need to in order to really solve this
为了真正解决这个问题
thing backwards you have to think about
倒退的事情你必须考虑
well I think the other player is going
好吧，我认为其他玩家会
to do this in a certain situation and
在特定情况下做到这一点
then you backup and that you know the
然后您备份，并且您知道
the demands that are placed on players
对玩家的要求
in that situation are it can be quite
在那种情况下
difficult to meet as the game becomes
游戏变得难以相遇
more complicated another thing to say
更复杂的另一句话要说
about this is there there is some
关于这个有一些
controversy in game theory about the
关于博弈论的争论
ideas behind things like backward
落后的想法
induction and part of that is that you
归纳法，其中一部分是你
know the according to the theory there
根据那里的理论知道
are certain parts of the game that you
是您游戏中的某些部分
should never see yourself in and then
永远不应该看到自己，然后
you could begin to ask the question okay
你可以开始问这个问题了
well let's suppose we really did end up
好吧，假设我们真的结束了
there what should I believe about the
那我应该相信什么
other player how did we get there so
其他玩家我们如何到达那里
there's there's it's not so easy
那里不是那么容易
actually to to very carefully write down
其实要很认真地写下来
a foundation in terms of logical
逻辑上的基础
thinking which makes these predictions
做出这些预测的思考
and that's an interesting area of
这是一个有趣的领域
research
研究
so just to wrap up next time we'll be
所以下次我们总结一下
thinking a little bit about incomplete
考虑一点不完整
information and bringing that into the
信息并将其带入
study of games
游戏研究